I am just pointing it out
Ancak, modern zamanlarda
how, in the modern times, you have to be very careful
başkalarının dikkatini çekmeye çalışmamak için,
that you should not try to attract the attention of others.
nasıl çok dikkatli olmanız gerektiğine işaret ediyorum.
Instead of that, what you have to do is to pay attention to others
Bunun yerine yapmanız gereken şey, çok süptil bir şekilde
in a very subtle way, not with any expectation
başkalarına dikkat koymaktır, eğer birisine dikkat koyuyorsanız,
that if you are paying attention to somebody, that person should pay attention to you.
o kişinin de size dikkat koyması gerektiği
I’ve seen, in Sahaja Yoga also, that people try to, say, become very popular
Ben bunu gördüm, Sahaja Yoga’da da, insanların popüler olmak,
or become very outstanding, or something of a very great qualities,
göze çarpmak, kendilerinin çok büyük kaliteleri olduğunu, diğer insanlardan
to show off that they are something better than others.
daha iyi bir şey olduklarını göstermeye çalıştıklarını gördüm.
A person who is really in connection with the Divine, is least bothered
Tanrısal olanla gerçekten bağlantısı olan bir kişi, insanların o kişiye
about how people pay attention to that person,
ne şekilde dikkat ettikleri konusunda minimum rahatsızlık duyar
but automatically the attention of such a person is on others,
ama böyle bir kişinin dikkati otomatik olarak başkaları üzerindedir,
which is very, very subtle, very subtle.
bu çok, çok ince, çok süptildir.
You cannot make out that the attention of such a person
Böyle bir kişinin dikkatinin sizde olduğunu anlayamazsınız,
is on you, but it works and it works beautifully.
ama bu işe yarar ve çok güzel çalışır.
We have to understand that we have now come to the realm of the Divinity.
Şimdi Tanrısallığın krallığına geldiğimizi anlamalıyız.
We are in the Kingdom of God and we are divine people.
Tanrı’nın Krallığındayız ve bizler Tanrısal insanlarız.
We are very powerful people, but if we fritter away
Bizler çok güçlü insanlarız ama dikkatimizi dağıtırsak
our attention, we become very, very weak people.
çok, çok zayıf insanlar oluruz.
It's easy to feel that, “we are Sahaja Yogis”, “we have done
“Bizler Sahaja Yogileriz”, “başkalarının aydınlanması için çok şey yaptık”
so much of realisation of others” or “we have helped so many people.”
veya “biz çok sayıda insana yardım ettik” diye hissetmek kolaydır.
All this consciousness if it comes within you, then know
Tüm bu bilinç eğer içinizde olursa, o zaman bilin ki
that you are still not fully developed Sahaja Yogis.
hala tam olarak Sahaja Yogi değilsiniz.
There should be no consciousness of what you are doing or what you are committing.
Ne yaptığınız hususunda hiçbir bilinç olmamalıdır.
There is no need to boast about it. There is no need to advertise it.
Bununla övünmeye gerek yok. Reklam yapmaya gerek yok.
Whatever you are, is already, can be seen by everyone.
Her neyseniz, bu zaten herkes tarafından görülebilir
But even that desire is not needed
ama bu arzu bile gerekli değildir,
because you are doing just for the satisfaction of your Spirit.
çünkü siz bunu sadece Ruhunuzun tatminini sağlamak için yapıyorsunuz.
So then, when we come to our heart:
Öyleyse, kalbimize geldiğimizde:
in the heart resides the Spirit, as you know very well.
çok iyi bildiğiniz gibi, kalpte Ruh bulunur.
Now, when it is the heart, which has to work over your brain and which can work,
Şimdi bu şey, sizin beyniniz üzerinde çalışması gereken
what becomes of you is nothing, but you become a source
ve böyle çalışabilen kalp olduğu zaman, siz ne olursunuz, bir sevgi ve şefkat
of love and compassion. A source, I am saying.
kaynağından başka bir şey olmazsınız.
You do not assert on others. You do not say that, “I’ve done so much for you
Başkalarına karşı, “ben senin için çok şey yaptım,
and what are you doing to me? What is this that I should have so much expressed,
sen benim için ne yapıyorsun? Bu kadar yoğun şekilde
you are forgetting me and not doing anything for me?”
beni unutuyorsun ve sen benim için hiçbir şey yapmıyorsun?”
So the expectation of reward if it is there,
gibi beyanlarda bulunmazsınız. Yani orada
and is working it out that way that you just now put attention
ve bu şekilde çalışan şey aklınızdır ve şimdi, siz diğer bir kişiye
to the amount of love the other person has given you
her ne verdiyseniz, dikkatinizi diğer kişinin
for whatever you have given to another person. It's very subtle.
size verdiği sevginin çokluğuna koyarsınız. Bu çok süptildir.
So in Sahaja Yoga, you should see now yourself as just a source of love,
Öyleyse Sahaja Yoga’da, şimdi kendinizi sadece akan bir
which is just flowing.
sevgi kaynağı olarak görmelisiniz.
In that, you do not say that you have to have this or that,
Bunda, sizin şunu ya da bunu verdiğinizi veyahut sizin
or you have to achieve this goal, or you have to become that. It's finished now.
şu hedefe ulaşmanız gerektiğini ya da bu şey olmanız gerektiğini söylemezsiniz.
Once you have become the source, then how can you become something?
Bu bitti şimdi. Siz bir kez kaynak olduğunuzda, o zaman nasıl başka bir şey olabilirsiniz ki?
The thing is, those who are receiving from the source want to have
Mesele şu ki, kaynaktan alan kişiler bir tür ödül
some sort of a reward or some sort of a recognition.
ya da bir çeşit takdir görmek istiyorlar.
In this subtle way if you move, your mind is very clever.
Eğer böyle süptil bir şekilde hareket ederseniz, zihniniz çok akıllıdır.
In Sahaja Yoga, we have very clever, intelligent people.
Sahaja Yoga’da çok akıllı, zeki insanlarımız var.
But this mind... You have to be very careful because this mind can cheat you.
Ama bu akıl… Çok dikkatli olmalısınız çünkü bu zihin sizi kandırabilir.
So ask your mind, "Why are you in Sahaja Yoga?
Öyleyse zihninize sorun, “Neden Sahaja Yogadasın?
What is the purpose of your Sahaja Yoga?"
Senin Sahaja Yoganın amacı nedir?”
Gradually this mind will shut up. And then, you have to ask yourself that,
Yavaş yavaş bu zihin sesini kesecektir. Ve sonra, kendinize şunu sormalısınız,
"What is my own desire now? What do I want?
“Şimdi benim arzum nedir? Ne istiyorum?
What do I want to achieve? Why I am in Sahaja Yoga?"
Ne elde etmek istiyorum? Neden Sahaja Yogadayım?”
If you ask this question, you will see you’ll just dissolve,
Eğer bu soruyu sorarsanız, bunun sadece çözüldüğünü göreceksiniz,
you'll become thoughtless because there is no desire left now.
düşüncesiz olacaksınız çünkü artık arzu kalmadı.
There is no ambition left, no competition.
Hiç hırs kalmadı, rekabet yok.